# Muhammad Umar Anzar

# **Computer Scientist**

I am a final-year computer science student with a strong background in logic building and programming languages. I have worked on data science projects and am familiar with the fundamental front-end and back-end development technologies. I am a collaborative team player with good communication skills and a strong work ethic, and am determined to make a difference in the field.

#### **CONTACT INFO**

# +92 317 2456854

DHA Phase VI, Karachi

ia Phase VI, Karachi

omer.anzar2@gmail.com

github.com/umar-anzar

linkedin.com/in/umar-anzar

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Science Intern, the Sparks Foundation

April 2023 - May 2023

- Created ML models to analyze provided datasets, forecast hidden data, and evaluate model precision.
- Performed exploratory data analysis (EDA) procedures to learn new facts about the datasets.

# Al Research Intern, National Center for Cyber Security (NCCS)

March 2022 - April 2022

- Researched state-of-the-art algorithms for insider threat detection and gained exposure to various machine learning techniques such as recommendation systems and BERT.
- My brief internship experience sparked my interest in the field of machine learning and provided valuable learning opportunities.

## **SKILL HIGHLIGHTS**

	Programm	Programming Language	
Python	Java	JavaScript	
	C/C++	SQL	

	Mach	nine Learning
Numpy	SnapMl	Matplotlib
Scikit-learn	Pandas	Seaborn
		Scipy

Web Development

JavaScript NodeJs Html

ThreeJs ExpressJs Css

Database

**EDUCATION** 

2019- Present

CGPA: 3.57

MongoDb | PostgreSQL | SQL Server |

Parallel & Distributed Computing
Multi- MPI CUDA-C
Thread

**Bachelors in Computer Science** 

# **PROJECTS**

## Computer Vision and Object Detection API

- Collaborated with a team of three to develop a PYQT-based GUI hand gesture recognition application that interprets human hand gestures to form.
- Gained experience in using computer vision and object detection APIs, resulting in a functional and user-friendly application.

## Object-Oriented Programming Application (Haazir)

 Developed a service-providing application prototype in Java Swing GUI utilizing SQLite as the database with a team of three.

### Kaggle Challenge – Titanic: ML from Disaster

 Using manual & auto hyper parameter search and voting classifier for improved accuracy. Achieved 78.7% accuracy

#### 3D Procedural City Generation of Karachi using THREE.js

 Collaborated with a team member to develop a Procedural City Generation which includes: Random Buildings Generation, Custom Camera with three Perspectives, Quaid-e-Azam and Rickshaw Models.

#### Finite State Machines Turn Based Game (Finite Ball)

- A two-player 2D soccer game (Pygame) similar to air hockey.
- Transition-based movement and actual In-elastic collision physics.

# DA SKBZ College | Karachi 2017-2019

Intermediate (Pre-engineering)

Cambridge O level The Oasys School | Karachi 2015-2017

University of Karachi | UBIT

# ACHIEVEMENTS CER

# Procom'23-Data Science Competition

Achieved 3rd position

Kaggle Challenge - Titanic Achieved 78.7% accuracy

## CERTIFICATIONS

#### IBM (Coursera)

- Machine Learning with Python
- Python for Data Science and AI

#### University of Michigan (Coursera)

HTML | CSS | JS | Responsive Design

#### DataCamp

- Introduction to Statistics
- Introduction to Statistics in Python